Finding Aid for the J. Paul Getty Assorted Building Plans, 1906, 1941-1967, and undated IA20014
Institutional Records and Archives
Assorted building plans
1906,
1941-1967,
undated
Institutional Records and Archives
Ada Oil Corporation
Getty, J. Paul (Jean Paul), 1892-1976
J. Paul Getty Trust
IA20014
34.43 Linear Feet (2 boxes, 8 flat files)
Records consist of blueprints, architectural drawings, a photograph, and a manuscript, 1906, 1941-1967 and undated, that depict and describe buildings having some relationship to J. Paul Getty, the Getty family and Getty businesses.
Acquisition Information
The items in this finding aid originated in accession nos. 1986.IA.06 and part of 1986.IA.19 (transferred by the J. Paul Getty Museum).
Restrictions on Access
The records described in accessions 1986.IA.06 are available for use by qualified researchers.
The records in accession 1986.IA.19, subject to review for permanently closed information, are open to qualified researchers. Requests for access will be reviewed on a case-by-case basis.
The following records are permanently closed: records containing personal information, records that compromise security or operations, legal communications, legal work product, and records related to donors. The J. Paul Getty Trust reserves the right to restrict access to any records held by the Institutional Archives.
Scope and Content of Collection
Records consist of blueprints, blueline prints, architectural drawings, a photograph, and a manuscript, 1906, 1941-1967 and undated, that depict and describe buildings that have some relationship to J. Paul Getty, the Getty family and Getty businesses. These include the Melody Lane Building on Wilshire Boulevard, Los Angeles, commissioned by Ada Oil, one of the Getty family oil companies; One Wilshire, Los Angeles, which was the headquarters of a number of Getty family businesses; 624 S. Grand Avenue, Los Angeles, the proposed site of a J. Paul Getty Museum; additions to houses owned by J. Paul and George Getty, both in Los Angeles; and two projects, the Mobridge Municipal Swimming Pool and the Hot Creek Hatchery, locations unknown.
Organization
These records are organized in three series: Series I. Commercial buildings, 1906, 1941, 1966-1967, undated; Series II. Residential buildings, 1948, undated; Series III. Other structures, 1939-1940, undated.
Bibliography
Information in the biographical note on J. Paul Getty was adapted from:
Walsh, John and Deborah Gribbon. The J. Paul Getty Museum and its collections: a museum for the new century. Los Angeles: J. Paul Getty Museum, 1997.
Architecture -- California -- Los Angeles; Manuscripts; Architectural drawings (visual works); Photographs; Blueline prints; Blueprints (reprographic copies); Getty, J. Paul (Jean Paul), 1892-1976; Getty, George F. (George Franklin), 1855-1930
- Commercial buildings, 1906; 1941,; 1966-1967,; undated; Series I.; 14 Linear Feet (1 box, 3 flat files)
  Arrangement
  These records are arranged by building and by date.
  Scope and Contents note
  Records consist of blueline prints, photocopies of blueline prints, and a photograph, 1906, 1941, 1966-1967, and undated, of three commercial buildings having some connection to J. Paul Getty and the Getty family businesses. The commercial building with retail outlets proposed for the corner of Wilshire Boulevard and Western Avenue was commissioned by Ada Oil (listed as "owner" on the first blueline print), one of the Getty family oil corporations. One Wilshire, Los Angeles, was the headquarters of some of the Getty family businesses. 624 S. Grand Avenue, Los Angeles, was the site of a proposed J. Paul Getty Museum.
  - Melody Lane job, Wilshire and Western:
    General note
    [Photocopies of blueline prints.]
    - Elevation, November 1941 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-16)
    - Foundation plan, November 1941 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-16)
    - Electrical, wiring, plumbing and fixture plan, November 1941 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-16)
    - Plumbing diagram, November 1941 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-16)
    - Section details, November 1941; [2 sheets.] (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-16)
    - Roof plan, November 1941 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-16)
    - Plot plan, November 1941 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-16)
    - Dining room details, November 1941 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-16)
    - Elevation and scale details, November 1941 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-16)
    - Details of Ingraham St. entrance hall, November 1941 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-16)
    - Lobby details, November 1941 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-16)
    - Wall elevations, November 1941 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-16)
  - One Wilshire Building, 22nd floor, Nisso Pacific Corp., Saphier, Lerner, Schindler, Inc. Environetics:
    - Elevation, November 28, 1966; December 2, 1966,; February 7, 1967 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-15)
    - Floor plan, November 28, 1966; December 2, 1966,; February 7, 1967 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-15)
    - Technical specifications, November 28, 1966; December 2, 1966,; February 7, 1967 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-15)
    - Photograph of corner of Wilshire and Hobart, 1906 (Box 1986.IA.19-18)
  - 624 South Grand Avenue:
    - "Legends/Section/Detail – Suite proposed for: J.P. Getty Museum 624 So. Grand Avenue Los Angeles, Calif. 90017, " Paramount Space Planning and Design, undated (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-15)
      [2 copies.]
    - "Demo. and Const. Plan/Reflected Clg. Plan/Phone and Elect. Plan/Fin. Schedule Plan – Suite Proposed for: J. P. Getty Museum 624 S. Grand Avenue Los Angeles, Calif. 90017," Paramount Space Planning and Design, undated (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-15)
      [3 copies.]
- Residential buildings, 1948; undated; Series II.; 12.26 Linear Feet (1 box, 3 flat files)
  These records are arranged by building type and by date.
  Records consist of blueprints, blueline prints, and a typed manuscript, 1948 and undated, depicting various Getty family residences. The records depict a garage addition to J. Paul Getty's house at 270 Ocean Front, Santa Monica, California; designs for pantries for an unidentified J. Paul Getty residence; and alterations to an existing residence for George Getty.
  - Garage Addition to Residence of J. Paul Getty, 270 Ocean Front, Santa Monica, Macco Corp. – Builder:
    - Floor plan, June 17, 1948 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-13)
      [Approval date on verso. 4 copies.]
    - Plot plan, undated (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-13)
      [4 copies.]
    - Plot plan, undated (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-13)
      [Pencil drawing on vellum.]
    - Floor plan, elevations, undated (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-13)
      [Pencil drawings on vellum; 2 versions.]
  - Unidentified J. Paul Getty residence:
    - "South Wall Pantry", undated (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-13)
    - "Pantry Cases; Getty Job", January 15, 1948 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-13)
      [4 views. One drawing is torn and has a piece missing from the lower right edge.]
  - George Getty Building:
    - Alteration plan for Mr. George Getty, Frank M. Tyler, Architect, undated (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-14)
    - "Alterations to be made on Residence of George F. Getty, on north-west corner of Wilshire and Kingsley Street,", undated (Box 1986.IA.06-01, Folder 1)
      [Typed manuscripts with handwritten notes on reverse.]
- Other structures, 1939-1940, undated; Series III.; 8.17 Linear Feet (2 flat files)
  These records are arranged by type of structure and by date.
  Records consist of blueprints and blueline prints, 1939-1940 and undated, depicting a detail for the Mobridge Municipal Swimming Pool and the Hot Creek Hatchery project, including general layout, details of cross dams, the supply pipeline, and the hatchery building. The relationship of the buildings depicted in the drawings to J. Paul Getty or the Getty family and its businesses is unclear.
  - Hot Creek Hatchery, State of California Division of Fish and Game:
    - "Hot Creek Project – General Layout", January 25, 1940 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-11)
    - "Hot Creek Project – General Layout", January 26, 1940 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-11)
    - "Hot Creek Project – Details of Cross Dams On Pond Systems", January 18, 1940 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-11)
    - "Hot Creek Project – Details of Center Flumes On Pond Systems", January 12, 1940 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-11)
    - "Hot Creek Project – Hatchery Water Supply Dam", December 28, 1939 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-11)
    - "Hot Creek Project – Details of Hatchery Supply Pipeline", January 14, 1939 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-11)
    - "Hot Creek Project – Details of Hatchery Building", undated (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-11)
    - "Hot Creek Project – Framing Detail [?] Building", February 16, 1940 (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-11)
  - Mobridge Municipal Swimming Pool:
    - "Municipal Swimming Pool for the City of Mobridge – Typical Wall Form Detail – National Swimming Pool Corp. 615 So. Oxford Ave., Los Angeles, Calif.", undated (Flatfile 1986.IA.19-14)